<strings>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_TUT1</id>
        <value>Click on NEXT TIP to cycle through all available tips. You can activate this help menu at any time by clicking on the MENU button and choosing HELP.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T1</id>
        <value>In UEDAIP Vanilla, balance is intentionally different from Brood Wars - this part of the mod attempts to explore how each race could've looked just before they've met and developed more efficient weapons.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G1</id>
        <value>To toggle subtitles on or off, go to MENU. Under OPTIONS, select SOUND and click on the box marked TOGGLE SUBTITLES.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T2</id>
        <value>Some maps will read saved data from an earlier map. This may let you gain some extra units, upgrades, or influence one of your opponents in some way.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G2</id>
        <value>Most commands in the game have hot keys.  These keys are denoted by the highlighted letter in the text of the command button.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G3</id>
        <value>To restart a mission, choose END MISSION from the menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G4</id>
        <value>Mission objectives may be viewed at any time by choosing MISSION OBJECTIVES from the menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T3</id>
        <value>Enemies in UEDAIP will often expand if allowed to, and benefit from the extra resources that they can gather. Be careful to not let enemy production get out of hand.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G5</id>
        <value>Terran Vultures can lay Spider Mines: select a Vulture unit, then select the MINE button and designate an area of ground as the target.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Ga</id>
        <value>Queue up to five units at the same time by selecting a building, then clicking on the button of the unit you wish to queue.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T4</id>
        <value>Ghosts deal two types of damage per attack and receive further damage bonuses from Ocular Implants.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G6</id>
        <value>In some missions, you must return specific units to a particular location, designated by a glowing Command Point Marker, called a \"Beacon.\"</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G7</id>
        <value>When building a Terran Command Center, Protoss Nexus, or Zerg Hatchery, try to place it as close to resources as possible.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T5</id>
        <value>Your enemies may sometimes only develop certain tech if they're allowed to get a new base.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G8</id>
        <value>Cancel any unit in a queue by clicking on its icon in the construction \"pipeline\" display.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G9</id>
        <value>Toggle the terrain information on and off in the Mini Map by pressing \\4TAB\\1.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T6</id>
        <value>Sometimes, you may need to focus on the objectives instead of spreading your forces too thin.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G10</id>
        <value>Toggle the Mini Map between Team Color Identification and Friend-or-Foe recognition modes by pressing \\4SHIFT+TAB\\1.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G11</id>
        <value>When using the MOVE command, your units will ignore enemy units as they travel to their destination.  In this way, you can also use the MOVE command to retreat.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T7</id>
        <value>Your enemy may sometimes try to bypass your defences or catch you off-guard with drops. Be mindful of enemy transports.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G12</id>
        <value>Move your units with the ATTACK command when you wish them to engage enemy forces along the way.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G13</id>
        <value>You can adjust the sound, music, and speech in the SOUND menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T8</id>
        <value>Lift-off can be used to not only secure expansions early, but also bring production structures to islands that need reinforcement.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G14</id>
        <value>You can adjust the game speed, mouse speed, and other speed settings in the SPEED menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G15</id>
        <value>In single player games, you can speed up or slow down the game by pressing the \\4+\\1 or \\4-\\1 keys.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T9</id>
        <value>In UEDAIP Vanilla, Yamato Cannons are cheaper to cast and deal splash damage around their main target.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G16</id>
        <value>Deselect an individual unit from a group by holding down the \\4SHIFT\\1 key while selecting that unit.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G17</id>
        <value>To single out a unit from within a group, either select the individual unit, or select that unit's wireframe from the status display.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_T10</id>
        <value>The more overwhelming the army, the less severe the losses. Make sure you're not just throwing your units into a meatgrinder - it's better to wait for some four tanks that could do some damage, instead of suiciding two of them into enemy fortifications.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G18</id>
        <value>Load units into a transport using the MOVE command. The transport will automatically move to meet the units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G19</id>
        <value>Unload units from a transport by clicking the UNLOAD ALL button and selecting an unloading area. Unload an individual unit by clicking on its wireframe.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z1</id>
        <value>The Protoss get better and better at dealing with large groups of enemies over time. Try to swarm them early, or establish good map control to deny them effective Tier 3 unit usage.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G20</id>
        <value>You can designate targets for your commands (MOVE, ATTACK, GATHER, etc.) using the Mini Map.  In this way, you can send units to distant locations without having to scroll the Main Screen.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G21</id>
        <value>Click and drag in the Mini Map to rapidly scroll your view in the main screen.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z2</id>
        <value>The Ion Cannon will fire over all units flying over open space. Its projectile has a significant delay at long ranges, but is absolutely devastating if it hits.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G22</id>
        <value>To select a unit's previous group, hold down the \\4ALT\\1 key while selecting that unit.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G23</id>
        <value>SAVE your game frequently. If you find yourself in a desperate situation, you can go back and LOAD your game before you got into this whole mess.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z3</id>
        <value>All Zerg buildings, except the Hatchery, Creep Colony and Extractor, must be constructed on creep. Creep can be created by building a Hatchery or a Creep Colony.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G24</id>
        <value>Use the Campaign Editor, found on the Main Menu, to build your own maps and edit unit variables.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G25</id>
        <value>You can turn off unit responses in the SOUND menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z4</id>
        <value>Daggoth's Tiamat Brood has access to powerful Sunken Colonies and Hunter Killers, that regenerate their health with incredible speed.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G26</id>
        <value>The \\4SHIFT\\1 key allows you to chain together multiple commands. Hold down the SHIFT key while issuing commands; the unit will finish each task before proceeding to the next.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G27</id>
        <value>You can use the PATROL command to setup a patrol route for your units.  While in patrol mode your units will attack any enemy units that they see.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z5</id>
        <value>The Baelrog Brood receives resources from sacrifices, as well as from killing enemy units. Make sure to keep it well-fed, or else it may want to take a bite of your Brood by force.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G28</id>
        <value>Stationary combat units are assumed to be on guard: if they see an enemy unit they will automatically engage it.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G29</id>
        <value>Using the HOLD POSITION command, units will remain stationary, even if attacked, and attack enemy units within their range.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z6</id>
        <value>Groups of enemies that are hostile to eachother can fight eachother without your intervention. Don't be surprised if the map state changes a bit without your knowledge!</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G30</id>
        <value>You can setup convoys by selecting your escorts and telling them to MOVE onto the unit you want escorted.  They will then follow the designated unit.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G31</id>
        <value>To send messages to your opponent during multiplayer games, press \\4Enter\\1, type in your message and press \\4Enter\\1 again.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z7</id>
        <value>If you're struggling, don't be afraid to SAVE. Use ALT+S to quickly SAVE a mission and ALT+L to quickly LOAD a mission.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G32</id>
        <value>You can form alliances during a multiplayer game using the DIPLOMACY button on the Command Console.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G33</id>
        <value>During multiplayer games, allies achieve a shared victory only if all surviving allies have selected ALLIED VICTORY from the DIPLOMACY MENU.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z8</id>
        <value>Kerrigan is a very powerful hero that can kill groups of units on her own, but even she can fall without support. Make sure to keep track of where she is, and how healthy she is!</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G34</id>
        <value>In a multiplayer game, allies can share their fog of war information once all members of the alliance select SHARE VISION from the DIPLOMACY MENU.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G35</id>
        <value>Pressing \\4CTRL-S\\1 will toggle the sound on or off.  \\4CTRL-M\\1 will toggle the music on or off.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z9</id>
        <value>Offense is the best defense. Exploit gaps in enemy defense to take out enemy bases before they can hit you with their full might.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G36</id>
        <value>To surrender during a campaign or multiplayer game, use the SURRENDER button in the OPTIONS menu.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_Z10</id>
        <value>Some Dark Templar may try to run straight past your units, or even use Shuttles to escape. Make sure to maintain good vision of each exit.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G37</id>
        <value>Keep the path between the Command Center and available resources clear.  Obstacles slow the rate at which resources can be returned.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P1</id>
        <value>The Shelak Tribe has powerful High Templar that can use Psionic Storms to make their fellow warriors more powerful.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G38</id>
        <value>To save your current position on the map, press \\4Shift-F2\\1. To recall that position at any time, press \\4F2\\1. You can save up to three views using keys F2-F4 in this manner.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P2</id>
        <value>In some missions, you may have an increased supply cap. Use it to keep some defensive troops even while attacking - the time they afford you may come in clutch.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G39</id>
        <value>Different units are designed to work together and support each other. Combinations are more effective than a force composed of a single unit type.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P3</id>
        <value>Be mindful of ambushes! The insidious Zerg may try to get some troops behind you as you move around the map.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G40</id>
        <value>Hold down \\4CTRL\\1 while selecting a unit to select all units of the same type within your view.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P4</id>
        <value>Enemy Zerg can use Nydus Canals to produce units. Destroying them is an extra way to slow down enemy production in some maps.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G41</id>
        <value>Double-click a unit to select all units of the same type within your view.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P5</id>
        <value>Specific enemies will have specific ways in which they try to defeat you. Keep in mind what Broods, Squadrons or Tribes you're up against.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G42</id>
        <value>Pressing the space bar will center the screen on the location of your last transmission.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P6</id>
        <value>When controlling multiple races, remember that upgrading them both may stretch you thin on resources.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G43</id>
        <value>To save your currently selected group of units, press \\4CTRL-1\\1. To recall that group at any time, press \\0041\\1. You can save up to ten groups using keys 1 through 0 in this manner. This also works for buildings.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P7</id>
        <value>Destroying any of the abandoned Terran installations throughout the map will put you on Duke's radar - as far as he can spare anything that's not fighting the Zerg, anyway.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G44</id>
        <value>In a multiplayer game, pressing \\4SHIFT-ENTER\\1 sends your message to all players.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P8</id>
        <value>Infested Terrans in this installation are not quite as deadly as the ones you've met before. Nonetheless, don't be afraid to SAVE! Use ALT+S to quickly SAVE a mission and ALT+L to quickly LOAD a mission.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G45</id>
        <value>In a multiplayer game, pressing \\4CTRL-ENTER\\1 sends a message that is exclusive to your allies.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P9</id>
        <value>Infested Terrans in this installation are not quite as deadly as the ones you've met before. Nonetheless, don't be afraid to SAVE! Use ALT+S to quickly SAVE a mission and ALT+L to quickly LOAD a mission.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G46</id>
        <value>Units caught in an Arbiter's Stasis Field can neither attack nor be attacked for the duration of the spell.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_P10</id>
        <value>Your allies can help, but they are not strong enough to win on their own. Consider them as a way to save your own resources and supply.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_G47</id>
        <value>In Greed and Slaughter Mutiplayer games, a leaderboard displays the current leader. Press \\4CTRL-R\\1 to toggle between displaying the leader, and displaying all players.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP1</id>
        <value>Arbiters are expensive and replacing them clogs up enemy production. Try focusing them down with speedy units whenever you can.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP2</id>
        <value>Enemy casters will try to disrupt your armies whenever possible. Sometimes spreading out your units may be the only possible course.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP3</id>
        <value>The Overmind will defend fiercely, use special Zerg strains, and react with large groups of units even to small attack forces. Don't waste your warrior's lives on attacks that aren't decisive.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP4</id>
        <value>Protoss Reavers can be used to effectively defend your base and to quickly destroy enemy towns. Keep them protected by other units, since they are slow and vulnerable.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP5</id>
        <value>Select a unit and press the \\4H\\1 key to have the unit hold-ground, which will prevent it from wandering into enemy territory.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP6</id>
        <value>Expand and establish new bases early in the game. Having a constant supply of minerals and gas is essential to victory.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP7</id>
        <value>Merge Dark Templar to create Dark Archons. Select two Dark Templars and press the DARK ARCHON MELD button to create a Dark Archon. Dark Archons have the ability to MIND CONTROL enemy units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XP8</id>
        <value>Photon Cannons can fire at both ground and air targets, making them ideal for defending your base or other locations.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT1</id>
        <value>All Zerg buildings, except the Hatchery, Creep Colony and Extractor, must be constructed on creep. Creep can be created by building a Hatchery or a Creep Colony.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT2</id>
        <value>Medics automatically HEAL nearby organic units. Mix Medics together with your Marines or Firebats to increase their life expectancy.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT3</id>
        <value>Use Comsat to spot for your Siege Tanks. Build a Comsat Station at your Command Center and use the SENSOR SWEEP to reveal high ground and other hidden terrain you wish your tanks to attack.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT4</id>
        <value>Use the Medic RESTORATION ability to remove the effects of LOCKDOWN and other abnormal effects from your units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT5a</id>
        <value>Build Missile Towers to detect enemy Ghosts and to stop Nuclear Missile attacks. You can stop the attack by killing the Ghost before the missile lands.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT5b</id>
        <value>Use the Ghost LOCKDOWN ability to stop Battlecruisers and other mechanical enemy troops.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT6</id>
        <value>Valkyrie Frigates have splash damage and are very effective at destroying masses of enemy air units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XT8</id>
        <value>Block entrances to your bases with Bunkers and Supply Depots to slow down invading enemy units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ1</id>
        <value>Be mindful of ambushes! The Zerg may try to get some troops behind you as you move around the map.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ3</id>
        <value>Queens have the ability to INFEST a severely damaged Terran Command Center. Once infested, the Command Center is now a Zerg structure capable of building Infested Terrans that explode when attacking.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ4</id>
        <value>Use multiple Hatcheries to build a large number of forces quickly.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ5</id>
        <value>Use Overlords to spot hidden Spider Mines and cloaked units.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ6</id>
        <value>You can build Nydus Canals on enemy Zerg Creep. This is a quick way to transport your forces for an attack.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ7</id>
        <value>Upgrade your Ultralisks for faster movement and tougher armor.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_TIP_XZ8</id>
        <value>Use the Devourer's Acid Spore attack to slow down an enemy unit's rate of fire and reduce its armor. The effect is cumulative, and is best combined with other attacking forces.</value>
    </string>
    <string>
        <id>STR_LAST_TIP</id>
        <value>&lt;&lt;PLACEHOLDER&gt;&gt;</value>
    </string>
</strings>